paydayone.com 2013-11-08

# Privacy Policy and Information - RISE

_RISE_ Privacy Policy | Ohio CSO Privacy Policy | Ohio CSO Lender Privacy Policy Texas CSO Privacy Policy| Texas CSO Lender Privacy Policy

_RISE_ PRIVACY POLICY

EFFECTIVE JUNE 2013

facts| What does _RISE_ do with your personal information  
---|---  
Why?| Financial companies choose how they share your personal information. Federal law gives consumers the right to limit some but not all sharing. Federal law also requires us to tell you how we collect, share, and protect your personal information. Please read this notice carefully to understand what we do.  
What?| The types of personal information we collect and share depend on the product or service you have with us. This information can include: 

  * Social Security number and income 
  * Account balances and payment history 
  * Credit history and credit scores.

How?| All financial companies need to share customers’ personal information to run their everyday business. In the section below, we list the reasons financial companies can share their customers’ personal information; the reasons _RISE_ chooses to share; and whether you can limit this sharing.  
Reasons we can share your personal information| Does _RISE_ share?| Can you limit this sharing?  
---|---|---  
**For our everyday business purposes** – such as to process your transactions, maintain your account(s), respond to court orders and legal investigations, prevent or mitigate fraud, engage in corporate transactions, or report to credit bureaus| Yes| No  
**For our marketing purposes** – to offer our products and services to you| Yes| No  
**For joint marketing with other financial companies**|  Yes| No  
**For our affiliates’ everyday business purposes** – information about your transactions and experiences| Yes| No  
**For our affiliates’ everyday business purposes** – information about your creditworthiness| Yes| Yes  
**For our affiliates to market to you**|  Yes| Yes  
**For nonaffiliates to market to you**|  Yes| Yes  
To limit our sharing | 

  * Call (866) 580-1226 to speak to an account representative;
  * Visit us online: [www.risecredit.com](http://www.risecredit.com/); or
  * Contact us via email: [support@risecredit.com](mailto:support@risecredit.com).

If you are a new customer, we can begin sharing your information thirty (30) days from the date we sent this notice. When you are no longer a customer, we continue to share your information as described in this notice.

However, you can contact us at any time to limit our sharing.  
  
---|---  
Questions? | Call (866) 580-1226 or go to [www.risecredit.com](http://www.risecredit.com/)  
What we do  
---  
How does _RISE_ protect my personal information? | 

To protect your personal information from unauthorized access and use, we use security measures that comply with federal law. These measures include computer safeguards and secured files and buildings.

We also maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards (i.e., computer virus protection software, firewalls, 128-bit Secure Socket Layer). Only authorized employees have access.  
  
How does _RISE_ collect my personal information? | 

We collect your personal information, for example, when you

  * Apply for a loan 
  * Give us your income information
  * Provide employment information
  * Provide account information 
  * Give us your contact information 

We also collect your personal information from others, such as credit bureaus, affiliates, or other companies.  
  
Why can’t I limit all sharing? |  Federal law gives you the right to limit only: 

  * Sharing for affiliates’ everyday business purposes-information about your creditworthiness;
  * Affiliates from using your information to market to you; and
  * Sharing for nonaffiliates to market to you.

State laws and individual companies may give you additional rights to limit sharing. See below for more on your rights under state law.   
Definitions  
Affiliates | 

Financial and nonfinancial companies related by common ownership or control.

  * _Our affiliates include companies that have common corporate ownership with _RISE_ , such as Think Finance, Inc., TC Loan Service, LLC, Tailwind Marketing, LLC, TC Decision Sciences, LLC, and Presta Holdings, LLC._

Nonaffiliates | 

Financial and nonfinancial companies not related by common ownership or control.

  * _Nonaffiliates we share with can include direct marketing companies for application resell, direct mail and other purposes._

Joint Marketing | 

A formal agreement between nonaffiliated financial companies that together market financial products or services to you.

  * _Our joint marketing partners include financial institutions, credit card companies, partners that promote our products, pre-paid debit card providers and other lending companies._

Other Important Information  
---  
  
As part of our credit underwriting and information collection process, we will consider bank account information provided by you and we may detect additional bank accounts under your ownership. We also may collect and consider information about you from non-credit reporting agency data providers and publicly available information about you.

**Vermont residents:** We will not disclose information about you with affiliates or non-affiliated, third-party companies or financial institutions, other than as required or permitted by law, without your express permission.

**California residents:** We will not share information we collect about you with affiliated or non-affiliated third-parties, except in the limited circumstances permitted under state law, or if you give us your permission.

**North Dakota residents:** We will not disclose information about you with non-affiliated, third-party companies or financial institutions, other than as required or permitted by law, without your express permission.

**Nevada residents:** If you would like more information regarding this notice or Nevada’s law regarding corporate do-not-call registries, you can contact us at the toll-free number or address included in this notice or the Bureau of Consumer Protection, Office of the Nevada Attorney General at 555 E. Washington Street, Suite 3900, Las Vegas, Nevada 89101; Phone: (702) 486-3132/Email:[BCPINFO@ag.state.nv.us](mailto:BCPINFO@ag.state.nv.us)  
  
_RISE_ – OHIO CSO PRIVACY POLICY

EFFECTIVE JUNE 2013

facts| WHAT DOES PAYDAY ONE EXPRESS OF OHIO, LLC D/B/A _RISE_ (“ _RISE_ ”) DO WITH YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?  
---|---  
Why?| Financial companies choose how they share your personal information. Federal law gives consumers the right to limit some but not all sharing. Federal law also requires us to tell you how we collect, share, and protect your personal information. Please read this notice carefully to understand what we do.  
What?| The types of personal information we collect and share depend on the product or service you have with us. This information can include: 

  * Social Security number and income 
  * Account balances and payment history 
  * Credit history and credit scores.

How?| All financial companies need to share customers’ personal information to run their everyday business. In the section below, we list the reasons financial companies can share their customers’ personal information; the reasons _RISE_ chooses to share; and whether you can limit this sharing.  
Reasons we can share your personal information| Does _RISE_ share?| Can you limit this sharing?  
---|---|---  
**For our everyday business purposes** – such as to process your transactions, maintain your account(s), respond to court orders and legal investigations, prevent or mitigate fraud, engage in corporate transactions, or report to credit bureaus| Yes| No  
**For our marketing purposes** – to offer our products and services to you| Yes| No  
**For joint marketing with other financial companies**|  Yes| No  
**For our affiliates’ everyday business purposes** – information about your transactions and experiences| Yes| No  
**For our affiliates’ everyday business purposes** – information about your creditworthiness| Yes| Yes  
**For our affiliates to market to you**|  Yes| Yes  
**For nonaffiliates to market to you**|  Yes| Yes  
To limit our sharing | 

  * Call (866) 580-1226 to speak to an account representative;
  * Visit us online: [www.risecredit.com](http://www.risecredit.com/); or
  * Contact us via email: [support@risecredit.com](mailto:support@risecredit.com).

If you are a new customer, we can begin sharing your information thirty (30) days from the date we sent this notice. When you are no longer a customer, we continue to share your information as described in this notice.

However, you can contact us at any time to limit our sharing.  
  
---|---  
Questions? | Call (866) 580-1226 or go to [www.risecredit.com](http://www.risecredit.com/)  
What we do  
---  
How does _RISE_ protect my personal information? | 

To protect your personal information from unauthorized access and use, we use security measures that comply with federal law. These measures include computer safeguards and secured files and buildings.

We also maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards (i.e., computer virus protection software, firewalls, 128-bit Secure Socket Layer). Only authorized employees have access.  
  
How does _RISE_ collect my personal information? | 

We collect your personal information, for example, when you

  * Apply for a loan 
  * Give us your income information
  * Provide employment information
  * Provide account information 
  * Give us your contact information 

We also collect your personal information from others, such as credit bureaus, affiliates, or other companies.  
  
Why can’t I limit all sharing? |  Federal law gives you the right to limit only: 

  * Sharing for affiliates’ everyday business purposes-information about your creditworthiness;
  * Affiliates from using your information to market to you; and
  * Sharing for nonaffiliates to market to you.

State laws and individual companies may give you additional rights to limit sharing. See below for more on your rights under state law.   
Definitions  
Affiliates | 

Financial and nonfinancial companies related by common ownership or control.

  * _Our affiliates include companies that have common corporate ownership with _RISE_ , such as Think Finance, Inc., TC Loan Service, LLC, Tailwind Marketing, LLC, TC Decision Sciences, LLC, and Presta Holdings, LLC._

Nonaffiliates | 

Financial and nonfinancial companies not related by common ownership or control.

  * _Nonaffiliates we share with can include direct marketing companies for application resell, direct mail and other purposes._

Joint Marketing | 

A formal agreement between nonaffiliated financial companies that together market financial products or services to you.

  * _Our joint marketing partners include financial institutions, credit card companies, partners that promote our products, pre-paid debit card providers and other lending companies._

Other Important Information  
---  
As part of our credit underwriting and information collection process, we will consider bank account information provided by you and we may detect additional bank accounts under your ownership. We also may collect and consider information about you from non-credit reporting agency data providers and publicly available information about you.  
  
_RISE_ – OHIO CSO LENDER PRIVACY POLICY

EFFECTIVE JUNE 2013

facts| What does _RISE_ do with your personal information  
---|---  
Why?| Financial companies choose how they share your personal information. Federal law gives consumers the right to limit some but not all sharing. Federal law also requires us to tell you how we collect, share, and protect your personal information. Please read this notice carefully to understand what we do.  
What?| The types of personal information we collect and share depend on the product or service you have with us. This information can include: 

  * Social Security number and income 
  * Account balances and payment history 
  * Credit history and credit scores.

How?| All financial companies need to share customers’ personal information to run their everyday business. In the section below, we list the reasons financial companies can share their customers’ personal information; the reasons _RISE_ chooses to share; and whether you can limit this sharing.  
Reasons we can share your personal information| Does RCL Finance, Inc. share?| Can you limit this sharing?  
---|---|---  
**For our everyday business purposes** – such as to process your transactions, maintain your account(s), respond to court orders and legal investigations, prevent or mitigate fraud, engage in corporate transactions, or report to credit bureaus| Yes| No  
**For our marketing purposes** – to offer our products and services to you| Yes| No  
**For joint marketing with other financial companies**|  Yes| No  
**For our affiliates’ everyday business purposes** – information about your transactions and experiences| Yes| No  
**For our affiliates’ everyday business purposes** – information about your creditworthiness| No| We don't share  
**For our affiliates to market to you**|  No| We don't share  
**For nonaffiliates to market to you**|  No| We don't share  
Questions? | Call (817) 533-2606   
---|---  
What we do  
---  
How does _RISE_ protect my personal information? | 

To protect your personal information from unauthorized access and use, we use security measures that comply with federal law. These measures include computer safeguards and secured files and buildings.

We also maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards (i.e., computer virus protection software, firewalls, 128-bit Secure Socket Layer). Only authorized employees have access.  
  
How does _RISE_ collect my personal information? | 

We collect your personal information, for example, when you

  * Apply for a loan 
  * Give us your income information
  * Provide employment information
  * Provide account information 
  * Give us your contact information 

We also collect your personal information from others, such as credit bureaus, affiliates, or other companies.  
  
Why can’t I limit all sharing? |  Federal law gives you the right to limit only: 

  * Sharing for affiliates’ everyday business purposes-information about your creditworthiness;
  * Affiliates from using your information to market to you; and
  * Sharing for nonaffiliates to market to you.

State laws and individual companies may give you additional rights to limit sharing. See below for more on your rights under state law.   
Definitions  
Affiliates | 

Financial and nonfinancial companies related by common ownership or control.

  * _Our affiliates include companies that have common corporate ownership with _RISE_ , such as Think Finance, Inc., TC Loan Service, LLC, Tailwind Marketing, LLC, TC Decision Sciences, LLC, and Presta Holdings, LLC._

Nonaffiliates | 

Financial and nonfinancial companies not related by common ownership or control.

  * _Nonaffiliates we share with can include direct marketing companies for application resell, direct mail and other purposes._

Joint Marketing | 

A formal agreement between nonaffiliated financial companies that together market financial products or services to you.

  * _Our joint marketing partners include financial institutions, credit card companies, partners that promote our products, pre-paid debit card providers and other lending companies._

Other Important Information  
---  
  
As part of our credit underwriting and information collection process, we will consider bank account information provided by you and we may detect additional bank accounts under your ownership. We also may collect and consider information about you from non-credit reporting agency data providers and publicly available information about you.  
  
_RISE_ – TEXAS CSO PRIVACY POLICY

EFFECTIVE JUNE 2013

facts| WHAT DOES PAYDAY ONE EXPRESS2 OF TEXAS, LLC D/B/A _RISE_ (“ _RISE_ ”) DO WITH YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?  
---|---  
Why?| Financial companies choose how they share your personal information. Federal law gives consumers the right to limit some but not all sharing. Federal law also requires us to tell you how we collect, share, and protect your personal information. Please read this notice carefully to understand what we do.  
What?| The types of personal information we collect and share depend on the product or service you have with us. This information can include: 

  * Social Security number and income 
  * Account balances and payment history 
  * Credit history and credit scores.

How?| All financial companies need to share customers’ personal information to run their everyday business. In the section below, we list the reasons financial companies can share their customers’ personal information; the reasons _RISE_ chooses to share; and whether you can limit this sharing.  
Reasons we can share your personal information| Does _RISE_ share?| Can you limit this sharing?  
---|---|---  
**For our everyday business purposes** – such as to process your transactions, maintain your account(s), respond to court orders and legal investigations, prevent or mitigate fraud, engage in corporate transactions, or report to credit bureaus| Yes| No  
**For our marketing purposes** – to offer our products and services to you| Yes| No  
**For joint marketing with other financial companies**|  Yes| No  
**For our affiliates’ everyday business purposes** – information about your transactions and experiences| Yes| No  
**For our affiliates’ everyday business purposes** – information about your creditworthiness| Yes| Yes  
**For our affiliates to market to you**|  Yes| Yes  
**For nonaffiliates to market to you**|  Yes| Yes  
To limit our sharing | 

  * Call (866) 580-1226 to speak to an account representative;
  * Visit us online: [www.risecredit.com](http://www.risecredit.com/); or
  * Contact us via email: [support@risecredit.com](mailto:support@risecredit.com).

If you are a new customer, we can begin sharing your information thirty (30) days from the date we sent this notice. When you are no longer a customer, we continue to share your information as described in this notice.

However, you can contact us at any time to limit our sharing.  
  
---|---  
Questions? | Call (866) 580-1226 or go to [www.risecredit.com](http://www.risecredit.com/)  
What we do  
---  
How does _RISE_ protect my personal information? | 

To protect your personal information from unauthorized access and use, we use security measures that comply with federal law. These measures include computer safeguards and secured files and buildings.

We also maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards (i.e., computer virus protection software, firewalls, 128-bit Secure Socket Layer). Only authorized employees have access.  
  
How does _RISE_ collect my personal information? | 

We collect your personal information, for example, when you

  * Apply for a loan 
  * Give us your income information
  * Provide employment information
  * Provide account information 
  * Give us your contact information 

We also collect your personal information from others, such as credit bureaus, affiliates, or other companies.  
  
Why can’t I limit all sharing? |  Federal law gives you the right to limit only: 

  * Sharing for affiliates’ everyday business purposes-information about your creditworthiness;
  * Affiliates from using your information to market to you; and
  * Sharing for nonaffiliates to market to you.

State laws and individual companies may give you additional rights to limit sharing. See below for more on your rights under state law.   
Definitions  
Affiliates | 

Financial and nonfinancial companies related by common ownership or control.

  * _Our affiliates include companies that have common corporate ownership with _RISE_ , such as Think Finance, Inc., TC Loan Service, LLC, Tailwind Marketing, LLC, TC Decision Sciences, LLC, and Presta Holdings, LLC._

Nonaffiliates | 

Financial and nonfinancial companies not related by common ownership or control.

  * _Nonaffiliates we share with can include direct marketing companies for application resell, direct mail and other purposes._

Joint Marketing | 

A formal agreement between nonaffiliated financial companies that together market financial products or services to you.

  * _Our joint marketing partners include financial institutions, credit card companies, partners that promote our products, pre-paid debit card providers and other lending companies._

Other Important Information  
---  
  
As part of our credit underwriting and information collection process, we will consider bank account information provided by you and we may detect additional bank accounts under your ownership. We also may collect and consider information about you from non-credit reporting agency data providers and publicly available information about you.  
  
_RISE_ – TEXAS CSO LENDER PRIVACY POLICY

EFFECTIVE JUNE 2013

facts| WHAT DOES SGS FINANCE, INC. DO WITH YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?  
---|---  
Why?| Financial companies choose how they share your personal information. Federal law gives consumers the right to limit some but not all sharing. Federal law also requires us to tell you how we collect, share, and protect your personal information. Please read this notice carefully to understand what we do.  
What?| The types of personal information we collect and share depend on the product or service you have with us. This information can include: 

  * Social Security number and income 
  * Account balances and payment history 
  * Credit history and credit scores.

If you are a new customer, we can begin sharing your information thirty (30) days from the date we sent this notice. When you are no longer our customer, we continue to share your information as described in this notice.  
  
How?| All financial companies need to share customers’ personal information to run their everyday business. In the section below, we list the reasons financial companies can share their customers’ personal information; the reasons _RISE_ chooses to share; and whether you can limit this sharing.  
Reasons we can share your personal information| Does SGS Finance, Inc. share?| Can you limit this sharing?  
---|---|---  
**For our everyday business purposes** – such as to process your transactions, maintain your account(s), respond to court orders and legal investigations, prevent or mitigate fraud, engage in corporate transactions, or report to credit bureaus| Yes| No  
**For our marketing purposes** – to offer our products and services to you| Yes| No  
**For joint marketing with other financial companies**|  Yes| No  
**For our affiliates’ everyday business purposes** – information about your transactions and experiences| Yes| No  
**For our affiliates’ everyday business purposes** – information about your creditworthiness| No| We don't share  
**For our affiliates to market to you**|  No| We don't share  
**For nonaffiliates to market to you**|  No| We don't share  
Questions? | Call (817) 533-2606   
---|---  
What we do  
---  
How does _RISE_ protect my personal information? | 

To protect your personal information from unauthorized access and use, we use security measures that comply with federal law. These measures include computer safeguards and secured files and buildings.

We also maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards (i.e., computer virus protection software, firewalls, 128-bit Secure Socket Layer). Only authorized employees have access.  
  
How does _RISE_ collect my personal information? | 

We collect your personal information, for example, when you

  * Apply for a loan 
  * Give us your income information
  * Provide employment information
  * Provide account information 
  * Give us your contact information 

We also collect your personal information from others, such as credit bureaus, affiliates, or other companies.  
  
Why can’t I limit all sharing? |  Federal law gives you the right to limit only: 

  * Sharing for affiliates’ everyday business purposes-information about your creditworthiness;
  * Affiliates from using your information to market to you; and
  * Sharing for nonaffiliates to market to you.

State laws and individual companies may give you additional rights to limit sharing. See below for more on your rights under state law.   
Definitions  
Affiliates | 

Financial and nonfinancial companies related by common ownership or control.

  * _Our affiliates include companies that have common corporate ownership with _RISE_ , such as Think Finance, Inc., TC Loan Service, LLC, Tailwind Marketing, LLC, TC Decision Sciences, LLC, and Presta Holdings, LLC._

Nonaffiliates | 

Financial and nonfinancial companies not related by common ownership or control.

  * _Nonaffiliates we share with can include direct marketing companies for application resell, direct mail and other purposes._

Joint Marketing | 

A formal agreement between nonaffiliated financial companies that together market financial products or services to you.

  * _Our joint marketing partners include financial institutions, credit card companies, partners that promote our products, pre-paid debit card providers and other lending companies._

Other Important Information  
---  
  
As part of our credit underwriting and information collection process, we will consider bank account information provided by you and we may detect additional bank accounts under your ownership. We also may collect and consider information about you from non-credit reporting agency data providers and publicly available information about you.
